### Curriculum Vitae

### **NANCY NJOKI MWANGI**

P.O. Box 62000 - 00200 Nairobi - Kenya, Mobile No: +254 723 081 591

Email: nanciemartins.nm@gmail.com

### Personal Data

Gender	Female	
Date Of Birth	1 <sup>st</sup> July, 1993	
<b>Marital Status</b>	Single	
Religion	ligion Christian	
Nationality	Kenyan	
Mobile no.	0723 081 591	
Languages	English and Kiswahili (fluent- oral and written)	

### Personal Profile and Motivation

I am an energetic and enthusiastic person who enjoys and loves a challenge and achieving personal goals. I am a good team Player and a Business Leader and an excellent Fresh Food manager. I am mature and have qualities to bring to work place such as Professionalism, team work, Honesty, Hard work, organizational skills, efficiency and company Loyalty. I am very meticulous and I show pride in all the work I do, and work well under pressure or no pressure. I possess excellent verbal and written communication skills and am able to relate to a wide range of people, customers and employers. All these skills have been enhanced during all the work experiences I have gained and training.

# **Academic Qualification**

2013 – 2016 : JKUAT (Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology)

- Bachelor of Science in INDUSTRIAL BIOTECHNOLOGY (2<sup>ND</sup> Class Honors Lower division).

2015 - 2017: Institute of Advanced Technology (IAT)

- DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY. Grade: **Distinction** 

**2014: - Certificate** I.T User Support Professional and Project Management.

- JKUAT ENTERPRISES

#### JAN-FEB 2012: SAMFRITECH COMPUTER COLLAGE

(8 COMPUTER PACKAGES)

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Publisher
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Adobe PageMaker
- Programming

### 2008-2013: KAHUHIA GIRLS' HIGH SCHOOL,

KCSE (Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education)
 MEAN GRADE B +

1998-2007: ST. THOMAS CATHOLIC ACADEMY.

KCPE (Kenya Certificate of Primary Education)

- (Grade B+)

### Work Experience

**DEC 2016 TO DATE:** SANLAM KENYA.

- Business Development and Financial Advisor.

**2014 – 2016**: Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Food Science and Technology Department.

#### **ROLES:**

- ➤ Food production, Fresh Food management , Value Addition and Distribution.
- > Product marketing and promotion.
- > Food safety and food maintenance.
- Quality management Raw materials Examination, Testing for quality and storage.
- Providing quality products and services to the competitive local and global marketplace.

#### JULY TO SEPTEMBER 2016: EAST AFRICA BREWERIES LIMITED.

#### **EXPERIENCES**;

- Quality management Raw materials Laboratory
- ➤ Analytical techniques Analytical Laboratory
- ➤ Equipment verifications Analytical Laboratory

- Food safety and food maintenance
- > Product marketing and promotion.
- Providing quality products and services to the competitive local and global marketplace.
- > Standard operating procedures.
- > Being in the world of work.

# JUNE- SEPT. 2015: DIRECT SALES MAXIMUM MARKETING LIMITED (DSMAX. LTD.)

Sales Executive.

#### **ROLES AND EXPERIENCES:**

- Organizing sales visits.
- > Demonstrating and presenting goods.
- Establishing new businesses.
- > Selling the company's products and services.

# **AUGUST 2014:** KENYA AGRICULTURE AND LIVESTOCK RESEARCH ORGANIZATION ( KARLO).

Attachee: Food and Horticulture Laboratory.

#### **ROLES AND EXPERIENCES:**

- Microbiological propagation of plantlets.
- > Fresh food lab and stores management.
- Analysis of research samples such as soils, plants and water.
- > Capacity building through mentorship sessions.

### JUNE-JULY 2013: NAKUMATT HIGHRIDGE, WESTLANDS NAIROBI

Sales Marketer and Products Promoter,

### EXPERIENCES.

- > Business development, sales and marketing management
- > Fresh food management.
- > Managing customer orders and deliveries.
- Convincing the customers that my product is the best and convincing them to buy.

#### FEB-AUG. 2012: GICHAGI-INI SECONDARY SCHOOL

- Teacher and Mentor (Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Geography & Kiswahili)

#### **VOLUNTARY WORK**

- ROTARACT CLUB OF JKUAT in children homes, society clean-ups among others. Gained skills such as problem solving.
- The KENYA REDCROSS SOCIETY
- National Environmental management Authority ( NEMA).
- GOK (Government of Kenya)- Youth Enterprise Development fund Training and Mentorship officer.

### **AWARDS:**

- 1. WINNER, KENYA FOOD EXPO 2016
- 2. JKUAT / JKUSO INNOVATION AND ENTERPRENEUR OF THE YEAR 2015.
- 3. NOMINEE YOUNG INNOVATORS IN AGRIBUSINESS AWARD .
- 4. LIONS OF SCIENCE AWARD
- 5. NETFUND GREEN INNOVATIONS AWARD 2016

### Other Training, conferences and workshops Attended

- 1. Business Leadership and Management (YALI) Young African Leadership Initiative
- 2. JKUAT Scientific Conference 2015.
- 3. Leadership Training (African Leadership Ministries / JKUAT)
- 4. Training of Trainers (T.O.T) Training on Peer Education, Guidance and Counseling Psychology. (Ministry of Health, NASCOP / JKUAT).
- 5. JEMA (JKUAT Environmental Management Authority) Training on Waste Management (Including Electronic waste Management).

# Special Skills Acquired

- Strong communication, analytical and presentation skills.
- Business strategy and Entrepreneurship.
- Customer psychology and Business Development
- Excellent Knowledge, exposure and experience in ICT.
- Good Scientific research skills, Project management and writing skills
- Self-motivation, creativity, and ability to work with a variety of people, singly or as part of a team.
- Professional Food Handling, Management and Value Addition.
- Ability to work without supervision.
- Software and Applications Development
- Project management and leadership skills.

## Extracurricular activities

- Playing Handball, hockey and athletics. Swimming and team building.

### **HOBIES**

- Travelling.
- Reading novels.
- Socializing.
- carrying out community empowerment activities

### REFFEREES

1	Dr. Mose Peter Ogoti	Director, Biochemistry and Food Technology Department, Jomo Kenyatta university of Agriculture and Technology - JKUAT +254728957828
2	Rev. Fr Prof. Lawrence Njoroge. P.O Box 62000 – 00200, Nairobi. Phone no06752711	CHAPLAIN , LECTURER AND FATHER IN CHARGE, JKUAT CHAPLAINCY
3	Ms. Jane Waithera	Manager, Quality Department Kenya Breweries Limited. +254722745397